Guide to the Fred Meyer, Inc. collection 1922-2010
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Fred Meyer collection
1922-2010
Oregon Historical Society, Davies Family Research Library Research Library
Coll 199
Fred Meyer, Inc.
38 cubic feet 39 document cases, 27 flat boxes.
Collection of photographs, advertisements, internal memos, employee newsletters and scrapbooks from Fred Meyer, Inc., headquartered in Portland, Oregon with stores throughout the Western United States.
Historical Note
The first Fred Meyer grocery store opened in downtown Portland, Oregon in 1922. The store's founder, Fred G. Meyer, opened more stores in downtown Portland in the 1920s and 1930s, then expanded into the outlying areas of Portland and beyond. By the 1990s there were stores bearing the Fred Meyer name throughout Oregon, Washington, California, Idaho, Montana, Utah, Arizona and Alaska. In addition to the supermarket stores, Fred Meyer, Inc. also included jewelry stores, restaurants, federal savings and loan banks, print shops, bakeries, dairies and music stores.
Fred G. Meyer pioneered the concept of one-stop shopping, the idea that all household goods could be purchased at one store. At Fred Meyer stores, customers could buy groceries, clothing, auto supplies, furniture, appliances, hardware, garden supplies and more. Fred Meyer was also among the first to develop self-serve drug stores at a time when all pharmaceutical products had to be purchased through a pharmacist. Fred Meyer stores are also known for their advertising slogan, "My-Te-Fine," which was also the name of the in-house brand of packaged foods.
In the 1960s through the 1990s, Fred Meyer, Inc. expanded by acquiring many smaller grocery store chains throughout the West including Marketime and QFC in Washington, B&B Stores in Montana, Grand Central and Smith's Food and Drug in Utah, Valu-Mart in Alaska and Smitty's Marketplace in Arizona. In 1999, Fred Meyer, Inc. merged with Kroger, Inc., making the combined company the largest grocery store chain in the country.
Fred G. Meyer was born Frederick Grubmeyer in 1886 in Brooklyn, New York. He moved West in the 1900s starting in Alaska and eventually making his way to Portland, Oregon. He married Eva Chatfield Chiles who would become his business partner and the inspiration behind Eve's Restaurants which were coffee shops attached to many Fred Meyer stores. Fred G. Meyer died in 1978 at the age of 92. His will established a charitable trust to create a philanthropic organization now known as the Meyer Memorial Trust which is now one of the largest private foundations in the nation.
The collection includes materials from the stores' beginnings in 1922 and continuing through 2010. It includes materials from many Fred Meyer stores located throughout the Western United States, but the bulk of the materials originate from stores and facilities in Oregon. This collection concentrates on materials related to the stores and business of Fred Meyer, Inc. and not on the personal papers of Fred G. Meyer. There are nevertheless some personal materials of Fred G. Meyer as well as materials from many of the executives who worked at Fred Meyer, Inc.
Most of the collection consists of photographs taken in this 88 year time span. Subjects include: store opening celebrations; exteriors and interiors of the stores; company meetings and parties; merchandise displays; promotional events; portraits of management figures and product shots used in advertising. The photographs are dispersed throughout the collection. In addition to prints, the photography collection also includes slides, negatives, transparencies and hand-drawn art.
A sizable part of the collection also includes newspaper clippings of relevant news stories or print advertisements. Many of these clippings include the hand-written notes of Fred G. Meyer. Several large scrap books include an extensive collection of advertisements from the 1930s through the 1970s.
Annual reports were only published in those years when Fred Meyer, Inc. was publicly traded on the New York Stock Exchange. The collection of employee newsletters does have a few gaps, but is by and large a complete collection of the newsletters from 1949-2010.
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series A: Corporate History
Series B: Individuals
Series C: Stores
Series D: Annual Reports
Series E: Employee Newsletters
Series F: Promotions and Advertisements
Series G: Negatives and Transparencies
The collection was originally organized around 2010 by Fred Meyer employees.
The collection is open to the public.
Most materials in this collection were created by Fred Meyer, Inc. and its employees. The documents were assembled, arranged and stored at the Fred Meyer corporate headquarters in Portland, Oregon until 2010 when the materials and accompanying notes were donated to the Oregon Historical Society.
Acquired 2010, Library Accession 27171
Film/video removed to the OHS Film Archive:
Fred G. Meyer interviewed by Gerry Pratt (DVD, 1975)
A Day in the Life – Fred Meyer promotional piece (DVD, circa 1980)
Convention Center Opening (DVD, 1993)
Bill Hemenway interview (DVD, 1993)
Oregonian of the Century (DVD, 1999)
Smiths/Fred Meyer Merger news on CNN (VHS, 1997)
Fred Meyer/Smitty's TV spot (VHS, 1999)
Smittys to Fred Meyer conversion, employee training tape (VHS, 1999)
Fred Meyer Marketplace Phoenix Coverage (multiple news station clips) 1/31/99(VHS)
Fred Meyer Marketplace Phoenix Coverage (multiple news station clips) 2/2/99 (VHS)
Smith’s and Smitty’s on KPNX 1/8/99 (VHS)
KSAZ News FM 2/8/99 (VHS)
Oran B. Robertson memorial at Lewis and Clark College 8/20/99 (2 copies, VHS)
Meyer Private Selection Ad (circa 2000, VHS)
Cook & Tell promotion (circa 2000, VHS)
Eric Baltzell: A Retrospective / A Leader (VHS)
Eric Baltzell: And So On… / Just Because (VHS)
Imogen Robbin interviewed by Julie Piper Finley (circa 1990, 2 copies, Hi-8)
Audio tapes removed to the OHS Sound Archive:
Fred Meyer interviewed by Gerry Pratt (1975, cassette)
Imogen Robbin interviewed by Julie Piper Finley (original tape) (circa 1990, cassette)
Fred Meyer ads responding to union strike 8/24/94 (cassette)
Fred Meyer ads responding to union strike 8/26/94(cassette)
Smitty’s to Fred Meyer Marketplace PHX radio news coverage KTAK-AM 2/1/99 (cassette)
FM Marketplace radio coverage on KPYI AM and KTAR AM 2/2/99 (cassette)
Imogen Robbin interviewed by Julie Piper Finley (circa 1990, 2 CDs)
Artifacts removed to the OHS Museum:
Fred Meyer Marketplace Hat (1999)
Fred Meyer Marketplace Tote Bag (1999)
Fred Meyer Marketplace ball point pens with “What’s on your list today?” slogan (1999)
Smitty’s Marketplace magnets (1998)
Employee Merit Buttons (22 Total, circa 1980s)
Fred Meyer Holiday Blinking Buttons
Magnets advertising grand opening of Fred Meyer store in Ballard, WA (1999)
Special Edition Founder’s Blend Coffee Bag(circa 1990s)
25-cent Fred Meyer trade-in coins (circa 1960s)
Recipe boards from the Fred Meyer Candy Kitchen (circa 1950s-1960s)
The Northwest Companies Collection (Mss 2858) includes prospectuses and proxy vote statements for Fred Meyer, Inc.
The Business Collection 1830-2008 (Mss 1510) also includes ephemera related to Fred Meyer, Inc.
The OHS Film and Video archive has a collection of 16mm home movies filmed by Eva Meyer, Fred Meyer's wife, under accession number 18052.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Meyer, Fred G., 1886-1978.; Meyer, Fred G., 1886-1978--Photographs.
Fred Meyer, Inc.--Archives.; Fred Meyer, Inc.--Photographs.
Oregon--Business enterprises.
Display of merchandise--Oregon.; Display of merchandise--Oregon--Photographs.; Grocers--Oregon.; Grocery stores--Oregon.; Grocery stores--Oregon--Photographs.; Retail trade--Oregon
Advertising and Marketing; City and Town Life; Retail Trade
Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs; Scrapbooks; Slides (photographic); Negatives (photographs); Color transparencies
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Fred Meyer Corporate History, 1922-2010; Series A
  The material in these folders relate to the general history, growth and development of Fred Meyer, Inc. It includes photographs from employee parties and meetings, information on acquisitions and mergers and news clippings about the company as a whole.
  - General History - Public Relations Materials, circa 1970-1999 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - General History - News Clippings and Correspondences, circa 1940-1990 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Business/Investing Reports, circa 1980-2000 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Employee Manuals and Publications, circa 1980-2000 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Gold Star Club, circa 1935-1999 (Box-folder 2/1)
    The Gold Star Club is a social and service organization of Fred Meyer employees. Most of the photographs in this folder come from the 1930s.
  - Gold Star Ball, 1935 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Gold Star Club Scrapbook, 1950s (Box-folder OSF-2)
  - Fred Meyer Christmas Cards, circa 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 2/3)
    Christmas cards sent to Fred Meyer employees from the Fred Meyer management team.
  - Fred Meyer Christmas Cards - Oversize, 1950s (Box-folder OSD-1/1)
  - Yamhill Street Fire, 1942 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Various Group Shots, circa 1930-1960 (Box-folder 2/5)
    Group shots of employees at meetings, parties and at work.
  - Early Store and Employee Photos, circa 1930s (Box-folder OSF-1)
    Scrapbook of photographs of stores, promotions, processing facilities and employee gatherings from the 1930s.
  - Fred Meyer Management Committee, circa 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 2/6)
    Photographs of and memos to various Fred Meyer executives.
  - Employee Profit Sharing, 1967 (Box-folder 2/7)
    Guidelines on Fred Meyer, Inc.'s profit sharing program.
  - Newspaper Article Clippings, 1959-1973 (Box-folder OSE-1/1-5)
    News articles regarding Fred Meyer, Inc. primarily from Oregon newspapers.
  - Oregon Journal Clippings, 1930-1982 (OSD-2/6)
    Photocopies of articles from the Oregon Journal subject files. Subjects include: Fred Meyer stores, Fred G. Meyer, Eva Meyer, Earle Chiles, Peter Mudie and the Fred Meyer Savings and Loan.
  - CB&S Advertising, circa 1960s-2000s (Box-folder 3/1)
    CB&S is a subsidiary of Fred Meyer, Inc. that handles all of its advertising and marketing. This folder contains memos, reports and accounting information.
  - General Merchandise Research Group Conference Report, 1971 (Box-folder 3/2-4)
  - Fred Meyer Graphics Manual, circa 1970 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Market Research Report (with FGM notes), 1975 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Employee Service Awards, circa 1980 (Box-folder 4/1)
    (Collection of buttons and pins removed to OHS Museum.)
    Negatives in Neg Folder 199-006
  - Generic Products, circa 1985 (Box-folder 4/2)
    Negatives in Neg Folder 199-005
  - Objectives Conference, 1987 (Box-folder 4/3)
    Negatives in Neg Folders 199-001 through 199-004
  - Employee Training, 1992 (Box-folder 4/4)
    Correspondence from Oregon Governor Barbara Roberts regarding Fred Meyer employee training standards.
  - Fred Meyer Listing on NYSE, 1992 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Union Strike, 1994 (Box-folder 4/6)
    (Audio cassettes of radio ads responding to the strike removed to OHS Sound Recordings.)
  - Oregon Flood, 1996 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Haggen Tanasbourne Opening - Fred Meyer response, 1996 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Research on Competitors' Stores, 1999 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Competitors' Ads - Oversize (originals), 1980s-1990s (Box-folder OSD-2/4-5)
  - Private Label News, 1999 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Private Selection Label Launch, 2000 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Northwest Best Launch - Research and Reports, 2002 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Northwest Best Launch - Promotional Materials, 2002 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Mergers and Acquisitions
    Material related to Fred Meyer, Inc's acquisitions of and mergers with other grocery store chains, primarily of photographs of the original stores before being converted to Fred Meyer stores and newspaper clippings.
    - Sigman's IGA - Roundup, circa 1960 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - B&B Stores (Montana), circa 1978 (Box-folder 5/2)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-007 through 199-008
    - Montana B&B Stores Newspaper Ads, 1967-1968 (Box-folder OSG-5/1)
      Advertisements primarily from the Daily Inter Lake News in Kalispell, Montana. These ads come from the time period immediately following Fred Meyer, Inc.'s acquisition of the B&B Store chain.
    - Warehouse Foods, circa 1980 (Box-folder 5/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-009
    - Grand Central Department Stores (Idaho), circa 1983 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Roundup Music, circa 1983 (Box-folder 5/5)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-010
    - Smith's Food & Drug (Utah), 1997 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - QFC/Ralph's (Washington, California), circa 1997 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Ralph's Fresh Fare Marketing, circa 1997 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Smitty's Marketplace (Arizona)- Photographs, 1997 (Box-folder 5/9)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-011
    - Smitty's Marketplace - Promotional Materials, 1997 (Box-folder 5/10)
      Hats, buttons, bags, etc. removed to OHS Museum.
    - Smitty's to FM Conversion - Reports and Plans, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 6/1-3)
    - Smitty's to FM Conversion - News Coverage, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 6/4)
      Videos and cassette tapes of news coverage removed to OHS Film and Video Archive.
    - Smitty's to FM Conversion - Photographs, 1999 (Box-folder 6/5)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-012 and Advantix cartridge in Negative Box #2.
    - Smitty's Acquisition and Conversion - Oversize, 1997-1999 (Box-folder OSD-1/2)
      Newspaper articles, advertising inserts and demographic maps related to Fred Meyer's purchase of Smitty's and its eventual conversion to the Fred Meyer name.
    - Fred Meyer (Arizona) to Fry's Conversion, 2000 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Fred Meyer-Kroger Merger and conversion to Fry's (AZ), 1998-1999 (Box-folder OSD-1/3)
- Individuals, 1886-2010; Series B
  This series includes documents relating to individuals connected with Fred Meyer, Inc., most of whom were executives in the company.
  - Fred G. Meyer
    Interview tapes and DVD, television news stories and audio cassettes removed to OHS Film and Video Archive and Oral History Department.
    - Fred G. Meyer - photographs and news clippings, circa 1930-1980 (Box-folder 7/1 - 4)
    - Fred G. Meyer - Stroke Rehabilitation Exercises, circa 1972 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Fred G. Meyer - Obituary Clippings, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 7/6 - 7)
    - Fred G. Meyer Memos and Notes, 1935-1978
      - FGM on Advertising, 1935-1978 (Box-folder 8/1-3)
        Smaller newspaper clippings with Fred Meyer's hand-written notes.
      - FGM on Advertising - Oversize (photocopies), 1935-1978 (Box-folder OSC-1/1-5)
      - FGM on Advertising - Oversize (originals), 1935-1978 (Box-folder OSD-2/1-3)
        Full-page newspaper clippings with Fred Meyer's hand-written notes.
      - FGM on Architecture/Interior Design, circa 1960-1970 (Box-folder 8/4)
      - FGM on Customer Service, 1970 (Box-folder 8/5)
      - FGM on Cost, 1970 (Box-folder 8/6)
      - FGM on Product Ideas, c1970s (Box-folder 8/7)
      - FGM on Office Efficiency, circa 1972 (Box-folder 8/8)
      - FGM on Employees, 1970s (Box-folder 8/9)
      - FGM on Signage, circa 1970 (Box-folder 8/10)
      - FGM on Instructions Upon Death, circa 1960s (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Other Fred Meyer, Inc. Individuals
    - Eva C. Meyer - photographs, 1935-1960 (Box-folder 9/1)
      Wife and business partner of Fred G. Meyer.
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-069.
    - Eva C. Meyer - memo, 1947 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Peter Mudie, circa 1935-1950 (Box-folder 9/3)
      Host of KOIN Radio's Consumer News show.
    - Jack Crocker, circa 1950s (Box-folder 9/4)
      President of Fred Meyer. Inc. in the 1950s and 1960s.
    - Earle A. Chiles, circa 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 9/5)
      Chairman of the Board of Fred Meyer, Inc. Also, Fred G. Meyer's step-son.
    - Irma Boone, circa 1950s (Box-folder 9/6)
      Marketing Manager, 1950s.
    - Oran B. Robertson, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 9/7)
      (Videotape of his memorial service removed to OHS Film and Video Archive.)
      Chairman of the Board, 1970s-1980s
    - Rollin Killoran, 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 9/8)
      Head of Marketing and CB&S Advertising.
    - Virg Campbell, circa 1980s (Box-folder 9/9)
      Executive Vice-President, 1970s-1980s.
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-021
    - Alan D. Ferguson, circa 1980s (Box-folder 9/10)
      President of Northern Region Stores and Executive Vice-President, 1970s-1980s.
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-022 and 199-070.
    - Imogen Robbin, circa 1980s (Box-folder 9/11)
      (Video and audio tapes of an interview with Imogen Robbin were removed to the OHS Film Archive and the Oral History Department.)
      Secretary to Fred G. Meyer.
    - Wesley Ebert, 1997 (Box-folder 9/12)
      Early Fred Meyer employee.
    - Cy Green - Advertising Artwork, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 9/13)
      President, 1980s and 1990s.
    - Cy Green - Photographs and Slides, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder 9/14)
      Color transparencies in Neg Folder 199-071.
      Black and white negatives in Neg Folder 199-072.
    - Gene Knutson, 2000 (Box-folder 9/15)
      Promotions Director, 1980s-1990s.
    - Robert G. "Bob" Miller, 1990s (Box-folder 9/16)
      Chairman of the Board and CEO, 1990s-2000s.
    - Robert G. "Bob" Miller, 1998 (Box-folder OSD-1/4)
      Copy of retail trade magazine featuring Robert Miller as Retailer of the Year.
    - Eric Baltzell, 2000 (Box-folder 9/17)
      (Videotapes from his retirement party removed to the OHS Film and Video Archive.)
      Senior Vice President, 1980s-1990s.
    - Dick Hodge, circa 1980 (Box-folder 9/18)
- Stores and Properties, 1922-2010; Series C
  - Support Facilities
    Consists primarily of photographs of Fred Meyer, Inc. support facilities including production factories, distribution centers and warehouses.
    - Mayonnaise Plant, circa 1940 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Candy Kitchen - photographs, circa 1940s-1950 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Candy Kitchen - recipes, circa 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 10/3)
      Recipe boards removed to OHS Museum, copies retained in folder.
    - Egg Plant, circa 1940s-1960s (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Dairy Plant, circa 1950-1960; circa 2001 (Box-folder 10/5 - 6)
      Color transparency in Neg Folder 199-073.
    - Bakery, circa 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 10/7 - 8)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-074, 199-075.
      Color transparency in Neg Folder 199-076.
    - Distribution Centers, circa 1950s-1970s (Box-folder 10/9)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-017, 199-077, and 199-078.
    - Main Administrative Office, circa 1963; circa 1985 (Box-folder 10/10)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-018, 199-079, and 199-080.
    - Main office interior, 1961 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Office interior and employees, circa 1985 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Salvage Department, circa 1980 (Box-folder 10A/1)
    - Retail Service Center (Chehalis, Wash.), circa 1990s (Box-folder 10A/2)
    - Distribution Trucking, circa 1990 (Box-folder 10A/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-019
    - Test Kitchen, circa 1995 (Box-folder 10A/4)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-020
    - Main Office Mailroom, circa 1985 (Box-folder 10A/5)
    - Photo plant, 1957; circa 1985; undated (Box-folder 10A/6)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-081.
  - Store Departments
    - Health House Natural Foods, circa 1930 (Box-folder 11/1)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-082.
    - Pharmacy, circa 1960s (Box-folder 11/2)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-083 and 199-084.
    - Nutrition Centers, circa 1972-1988 (Box-folder 11/3)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-013
    - Nutrition Centers - Oversize Ads, circa 1972-1988 (Box-folder OSD-1/6)
    - Savings and Loan, circa 1976 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Jewelry Department, circa 1980s (Box-folder 11/5)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-014
    - Eve's Kitchen, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11/6)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-015
    - FM Ready Print, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - NED Nutrition, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Home Electronics Department, circa 1983 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Home Improvement Department, circa 1985 (Box-folder 11/10)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-016
    - Meyer Food International, circa 1990 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Photo Processing Envelopes, 1970s-2000s (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Oregon Stores, 1930-2000
    - Insurance Report Photo Album, 1936 (Box-folder OSA-1)
      A photo album and report compiled by or for an insurance company covering Fred Meyer, Inc. The album details all properties held by Fred Meyer, Inc. as of 1936 including stores in Astoria, Salem, Vancouver and throughout Portland.
    - Unidentified Store Exteriors, circa 1930; circa 1995 (Box-folder 12/1)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-085.
    - Unidentified Store Interiors, circa 1955; undated (Box-folder 12/1A)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-086.
    - Aerial City Photographs, circa 1960 (Box-folder OSD-1-5)
      Aerial photographs marked with location of future stores or warehouses.
    - Corbett Building, 1909 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Hollywood Grand Opening, 1931 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Hollywood Exterior, 1931; 1949 (Box-folder 12/4 - 5)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-087 and 199-088.
    - Hollywood Interior, circa 1931 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Hollywood Interiors and Exteriors - Oversize, circa 1931 (Box-folder OSD-1/5)
    - Morrison at 3rd (Downtown Portland), circa 1935 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Morrison at 4th (Downtown Portland), circa 1935 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Morrison at 5th (Downtown Portland) - Exterior, 1942 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Morrison at 5th (Downtown Portland) - Interior, circa 1942 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Albany, Oregon, circa 1940 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Columbia Park/University Homes, 1943 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Montavilla - Exterior, 1943; circa 1945 (Box-folder 12/13)
      Negatives in Neg Folders 199-089 and 199-090.
    - Barbur Heights (Burlingame Location), circa 1950 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Burlingame Construction, 1950 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Burlingame Construction and Opening - Oversize, 1949; 1950 (Box-folder OSD-1/5)
    - Burlingame Exterior, 1950 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Burlingame Grand Opening, 1950 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Burlingame Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Original), 1950 (Box-folder OSD-3/1)
    - Burlingame Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Photocopy), 1951 (Box-folder OSC-1/6)
    - Burlingame Eve's Restaurant, 1961 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Hawthorne Construction, 1951 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Hawthorne Grand Opening, 1951 (Box-folder 13/7)
      Negative in Neg Folder 199-092.
    - Hawthorne Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Original), 1951 (Box-folder OSD-3/1)
    - Hawthorne Grand Opening Newspaper Section - Oversize (Photocopy), 1951 (Box-folder OSC-1/7)
    - Hawthorne Exterior, circa 1935; 1951; circa 1996 (Box-folder 13/8)
      Negatives in Neg Folder 199-091.
    - Hawthorne Interior, 1951; circa 1986 (Box-folder 13/9)
      Negatives (from 1986) in Neg Folder 199-023
    - Interstate Grand Opening, 1953 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Interstate Exterior, circa 1953 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Interstate Interior, circa 1951 (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Gateway Construction, 1954 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Gateway Grand Opening, 1954 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Gateway Exterior, 1954 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Gateway Interior, 1954; circa 1960s; 1997 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Division Construction, 1959 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Division Grand Opening, 1959 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Division Interior, 1959 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Division Exterior, circa 1959 (Box-folder 14/8)